Joyce Carol Oates Papers
Joyce Carol Oates Papers
- Writings
  - Essays
    - "Nostalgia: Dream, Memory, Poetry", Typescript ms.; Selection from Night Errands: How Poets Use Dreams / by Roderick Townley (Box 42)
    - "A Novelist Finds the Bare Bones of a Play" The New York Times, Nov. 18, 1990 (Box 42)
    - "On Boxing" The New York Times Magazine, Apr. 14, 1996 (Box 42)
    - "On Editing The Ontario Review", Typescript ms. (Box 42)
    - "On 'German Magic'", Typescript ms. (Box 42)
    - "On Original Works and Screen Adaptations", Typescript ms. (Box 42)
    - "On Suicide", Typescript ms. (Box 42)
    - "On the Art of the Short Story", Typescript ms. (Box 42)
    - "The One Unforgivable Sin", Work sheets; The New York Times Book Review, July 25, 1993 (Box 42)
    - "A Personal View of Nabokov", Typescript ms.; Saturday Review [n.d.] (Box 42)
    - "Phone Hex", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; The New Yorker - page proof; The New Yorker, Sept. 4, 1995 (Box 42)
    - "Plays as Literature", Typescript mss. (Box 42)
    - "The Powerful Allure of Mike Tyson" The New York Times, Oct. 25, 1987 (Box 42)
    - Prefaces by Joyce Carol Oates
      - On Boxing (Ecco Press), 1994; Typescript ms. (Box 42)
      - The Sophisticated Cat / chosen by Joyce Carol Oates and Daniel Halpern, Work sheets (Box 42)
    - "Rape and the Boxing Ring", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; Newsweek, Feb. 24, 1992 (Box 42)
    - "Rewriting The Scarlet Letter: Hawthorne Heroine Goes Hollywood", Typescript ms.; The New York Times, Oct. 15, 1995 (Box 42)
    - "Richard Wishnetsky: Joyce Oates Supplies a Missing View" The Detroit Free Press Magazine, Mar. 6, 1966 (Box 42)
    - "A Riddle Wrapped in a Mystery Inside an Enigma", Work sheets, page proof; The New Yorker, Dec. 12, 1994 (photocopy) (Box 42)
    - "The Romance of the Delaware Valley", Typescript ms. (working title: "The Delaware Valley: the Enchantment of the Counter-World"); Ford Times, July 1989 (Box 42)
    - "The Short Story", Typescript ms. (Box 42)
    - "Speaking the Same Language", Typescript ms.; The Buffalo News, Mar. 2, 1997 (Box 42)
    - "Speculations on the Novel", Typescript ms. (Box 42)
    - "The Style of the 70's: the Novel", Typescript ms.(working title: "The Novel in the 70's"); The New York Times Book Review, June 5, 1977 (Box 42)
    - "Success and the Pseudonymous Writer: Turning Over a New Self", Intermediate draft (working title: "Pseudonymous Selves"); The New York Times Book Review, Dec. 6, 1987 (Box 42)
    - "Sunday Drive 1948", Work sheets; Typescript ms.; Traditional Home, Mar. 1995 (photocopy) (Box 42)
    - "The Teleology of the Unconscious: the Art of Norman Mailer" The Critic, Nov./Dec. 1973 (Box 42)
    - "A Terrible Beauty is Born. How?" The New York Times Book Review, Aug. 11, 1985 (Box 42)
    - "There's No Place Like Home - Even If It's Impermanent" [n.p.] (reprinted from USAir Magazine), undated (Box 42)
    - "They All Just Went Away", Work sheets; typescript ms.; The New Yorker - galleys (Box 43)
    - "Thoreau As Psychologist", Typescript ms. (Box 43)
    - "The Tragic Vision of The Possessed", Typescript ms. (Box 43)
    - "Trespassing", Work sheets; The New York Times Magazine, Oct. 8, 1995 (Box 43)
    - "Unless We Share, We Are Not Fully Human", Typescript ms. (working title: "Community in America Now"); Galley; Life, Apr. 1991 ("Rediscover America" special advertising section: Community) (Box 43)
    - "An Unsolved Mystery", Typescript ms.; Between Friends / edited by Mickey Pearlman (photocopy) (Box 43)
    - "Updike's American Comedies" Modern Fiction Studies, Autumn 1975; signed "author's copy" (Box 43)
    - "The Vampire's Secret", Typescript ms. (Box 43)
    - "A Visit with Doris Lessing", Typescript ms. (Box 43)
    - "When Characters from the Page Are Made Flesh on the Screen" The New York Times, Mar. 23, 1986 (Box 43)
    - "Whose Side Are You On?" The New York Times Book Review, June 4, 1972 (Box 43)
    - "Why Is Your Writing So Violent?", Typescript ms.; The New York Times Book Review, Mar. 29, 1981 (Box 43)
    - "The Works of Charles Sheeler", Work sheets; American Artist, May 1998 (Box 43)
    - "The World's Worst Critics" The New York Times Book Review, Jan. 18, 1987 (Box 43)
    - "The Writer as Reviewer", Typescript ms. (Box 43)
    - "The Writer in Residence: Princeton Pastoral", Work sheets (working title: "At Home"); Intermediate drafts; House & Garden, June 1990 (Box 43)
    - "Writing in America" St. Louis Post-Dispatch, (incomplete), Dec. 7, 1969 (Box 43)
    - "The Writing Life: Tales Out of School", Work sheets (working title: District School #7, Niagara County, New York); The Washington Post Book World, Mar. 16, 1997 (Box 43)
  - Journal
    Ms. Oates journals are restricted. Written permission of the donor is required to access these items.
    - 1973-1978, July, 14 folders (Box 44)
    - 1978, Aug.-1979, Oct., 13 folders (Box 45)
    - 1979, Nov.-1980, Apr./May, 12 folders (Box 46)
    - 1980, May/June-1981, 14 folders (Box 47)
    - 1982-1985, 17 folders (Box 48)
    - 1986-1991, Apr., 14 folders (Box 49)
    - 1991, May-1993, 14 folders (Box 50)
    - 1994-1996, May, 12 folders (Box 51)
    - 1996, June-1997, Aug., 6 folders (Box 52)
  - Libretto
    - "Black Water", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Black Water: an American Opera" ([Philadelphia]: American Music Theater Festival), 1997; souvenir libretto distributed during the World Premier, Apr. 24-May 4, 1997, Philadelphia, PA (Box 53)
  - Poetry
    - "$", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "The Abandoned", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "American Holiday", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "The American Literary Magazine: an Artifact", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "American Merchandise" (working title: "Merchandise"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Autistic Child Twenty Years After, Scraping His Shoes", undated; Photocopy [n.p.] (Box 53)
    - "Ballad of Ashfield Avenue", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Benediction" The New York Times Magazine, Pt. 2, Oct. 9, 1983 (Box 53)
    - "The Black Glove: a Rapture", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "The Bullfrogs", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Compost" (working title: "Rinds, Husks, Leaves About to Fall"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "The Consolation of Animals", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Dakota Mystery, 10 May 1994", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Dead Friends", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Delayed Tryst, American Heartland", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Delusion", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Don't Bare Your Soul!", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Double Portrait", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Dream After Bergen-Belsen" (working title: "Codeine Dreams"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Edward Hopper's Nighthawks, 1942", Work sheets; Chicago Tribune Magazine, Sept. 25, 1994 (Box 53)
    - "Elegy: the Ancestors", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Emergency Room", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "The Eve of Your Death", Work sheet (Box 53)
    - "Falling Asleep at the Wheel, Route 98 North", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Fish" (working title: "Pond, Radiant with Gold"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Five Poems" The Texas Quarterly, Spring 1978; signed "author's copy" (Box 53)
    - "Flirtation, July 1953", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "The Floating Birches", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Frequent Flier I" (working title: "Terror of Flying"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Frequent Flier II" (working title: "The Adventure"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Gay Stand-Up Comic, Paramus, New Jersey", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "George Bellows' Mrs. T. in Cream Silk No. 1 (1919-1923)" (working title: "Catechism"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Glimpsed from a Car, Passing Quickly", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Hands, Prints, Time: a Collage" (working title: Being Fingerprinted"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "He Was Talking About His Friend", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "The Heir" (working title: "Final Visit"), Work sheet; The Massachusetts Review, Winter 1985 (Box 53)
    - "Honeymoon: Forty Years", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "The House of Mystery", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "How Delicately.. .", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "I Am Krishna, Destroyer of Worlds", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "'I Don't Want to Alarm You'" (working title: "Counsel"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "I Stand Before You Naked", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Immobility Defense", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "In Blue Nantucket", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "In Jana's Garden" (working title" "Harvest"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "In Memoriam", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "(In Parenthesis)", Typescript ms. (Box 53)
    - "In the Country of the Blue", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "The Infant's Wake", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Insomnia", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "The Insomniac", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Intensive", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Island, 1949", Work sheets; The Virginia Quarterly Review, Spring 1987 (photocopy); See also "Lost Creek" (Box 53)
    - "Last Exit Before the Bridge", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Like Walking to the Drugstore, When I Get Out" (working title: "Hate Mail"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Lines in Substitution for a Eulogy for a Dead Elder", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Locking Through", Holograph, typescript mss. (Box 53)
    - "The Lord Is My Shepherd, I Shall Not Want" (working title: "Anti-Poem, Upstate New York"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Lost Creek", Work sheets; The Virginia Quarterly Review, Spring 1987 (photocopy); See also "Island, 1949" (Box 53)
    - "Love and Terror" - selections from The Fabulous Beasts - Canadian Forum, Jan. 1975 (Box 53)
    - "Loves of the Parrots", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Makeup Artist", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Le Mal du Pays", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Mania: Early Phase" (working title: "Rinds, Husks, Leaves About to Fall"), Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Marooned in Dallas", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "Marrow", Work sheets (Box 53)
    - "The Miraculous Birth" The New York Times Magazine, Dec. 23, 1984 (Box 54)
    - "The Morning's First Futile Good Deed", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Nightmare, So Sweet" (working title: "Nightmare, Mid-summer 1985"), Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Nostalgia", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Off-Season", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Old Concord Cemetery", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "On This Morning of Grief", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Once Upon a Time" Prairie Schooner (photocopy), Fall 1987 (Box 54)
    - "Orion", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Peaches, Pineapples, Hazelnuts...", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Photography Session" (working title: "Mystery"), Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Piano Tuner", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Playground", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Prenatal", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Recollection, In Tranquility", Work sheets; The New Yorker - page proof (Box 54)
    - "Recurring Dream of Childhood" (working title: "Dream, July"), Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "The Riddle", Work sheets, "final revision" (Box 54)
    - "Rise Up, O Men of God", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Roller Rink, 1954", Work sheet (Box 54)
    - "Routine/Horror", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Season of Waiting" McCall's, Dec. 1991 (Box 54)
    - "Sexy", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "The Shattered Mirror", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "The Silence", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Skyscape" The New Republic, Feb. 5. 1977 (Box 54)
    - "Sleepless in Heidelberg", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Snapshot Album", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "The Stone Well", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Strait of Magellan" (working title: "Effigy"), Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Summer Squall, Monhegan Island", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Tenderness", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "There Was a Shot", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "The Thin Rain" (working title: "Penance"), Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "This Morning... " Prairie Schooner (photocopy), Fall 1987 (Box 54)
    - "The Triumph of Gravity", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Undefeated Heavyweight, 20 Years Old (I)", Work sheets; Prairie Schooner, Fall 1987 (Box 54)
    - "Undefeated Heavyweight, 20 Years Old (II)", Work sheets; Prairie Schooner, Fall 1987 (Box 54)
    - "Welcome to Dallas!", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "What Is Most American Is Most in Motion" (working title: "Resume Normal Speed"), Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "White Piano", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Winslow Homer's The Gulf Stream, 1902", Work sheets (Box 54)
    - "Wooded Forms" Albondocani Press, c1972 (Box 54)
  - Reviews
    - Book (by author) A-C, 5 folders of 24 (Box 54)
    - Book (by author) D-Md, 9 folders of 24 (Box 55)
    - Book (by author) Me-Z, 10 folders of 24 (Box 56)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 56)
  - Scripts
    - "The Adoption", Work sheets (Box 57)
    - "American Appetites" (screenplay), Typescript ms. and "plans for revision 2/27/91" (Box 57)
    - "American Holiday"
      - "American Holiday I", work sheets (Box 57)
      - "$", work sheets (Box 57)
      - "Procedure", work sheets (Box 57)
      - "Imperial Presidency", work sheets (Box 57)
      - "Whispering Glades", work sheets (Box 57)
      - "The Pact", work sheets (Box 57)
      - "I'm Waiting", work sheets (Box 57)
      - "Social Life; or, The Cannibals", work sheets (Box 57)
      - "The Suicide", work sheets (Box 57)
      - "American Holiday II", work sheets (Box 57)
    - "Bad Girls", Work sheets; Typescript ms. "revision" 1995 (Box 57)
    - "The Ballad of Love Canal", Work sheets (Box 57)
    - "Because It Is Bitter, and Because It Is My Heart" (screenplay), Work sheets; "Third draft 10/11/90"; "Final draft 10/29/90"; Typescript ms. "5-10-91"; May 1991 revisions (Box 57, 58)
    - "Black", Work sheets; "Revision" - undated (Box 58)
    - "Black Water", libretto; See Writings: Libretto
    - "Dawn", Intermediate draft (Box 58)
    - "Duet", Work sheets (Box 58)
    - "[The] Eclipse", Work sheets; "Production draft 3/9/90" (Box 58)
    - "Family" (screenplay), Work sheets; Typescript ms. (Box 58)
    - "Friday Night", Work sheets (Box 58)
    - "Good To Know You", Work sheets (Box 58)
    - "Greensleeves", Work sheets (Box 58)
    - "Gulf War", Work sheets (Box 58)
    - "Here She Is!", Work sheets (Box 59)
    - "Homesick", Work sheets; Intermediate draft (Box 59)
    - "How Do You Like Your Meat?", Intermediate draft (partial); Typescript ms. (Box 59)
    - "How Do You Like Your Meat?" - Long Wharf Theatre production scripts
      - Mar. 1991, (sub-title: "Short Plays by Joyce Carol Oates") with re-write pages (Box 59)
      - May 1991, update (sub-title: "an Evening of Four Short Plays by Joyce Carol Oates") (Box 59)
    - "I Stand Before You Naked"
      - "The Boy", intermediate draft (Box 59)
      - "Wife of... ", work sheets (Box 59)
      - "The Orange", work sheets (Box 59)
      - "Darling I'm Telling You", work sheets (Box 59)
      - "Wealthy Lady", work sheets (Box 59)
      - "Good Morning! Good Afternoon!", work sheets (Box 59)
      - "Pregnant", intermediate draft (Box 59)
    - "In Darkest America"
      - "Tone Clusters" (Box 59)
      - "Eclipse" (Box 59)
    - "In the Region of Ice", July 23, 1975; Screenplay adaptation by Peter Werner, based on the story of JCO - typescript ms. (bound) (Box 59)
    - "The Interview", Work sheets (Box 59)
    - "The Key", Work sheets (Box 59)
    - "Negative", Work sheets (Box 59)
    - "No Next of Kin", Work sheets (Box 59)
    - "The Passion of Henry David Thoreau", Work sheets; 2 folders (Box 59)
    - "The Perfectionist", Work sheets; "Early draft"; Typescript ms. draft (Box 60)
    - "Psychiatric Services", Typescript ms.; Typescript ms. (carbon) (Box 60)
    - "The Rehearsal", Work sheets (Box 60)
    - "The Sacrifice", Work sheets (Box 60)
    - "The Secret Mirror"
      - "The Human Fly", work sheets (Box 60)
      - "Secret", work sheets (Box 60)
      - "The Anatomy Lesson", work sheet (Box 60)
      - "I Don't Want to Alarm You", work sheets (Box 60)
      - "I Got Something for You", work sheets (Box 60)
      - "A Report to an Academy", work sheets (Box 60)
      - "The Psychic", work sheets (Box 60)
      - "The Secret Mirror", work sheets (Box 60)
    - "Snake Eyes" (screenplay)
      - Work sheets (Box 60)
      - Original first draft remnants (Box 60)
      - Synopsis of story and characters (Box 60)
      - Re-write, Sept.-Oct. 1992 (Box 60)
        - Draft (Box 60)
        - Typescript ms. (Box 60)
        - Ribbon copy (p. 63-106) (Box 60)
    - "Solstice" (screenplay), Work sheets; "2nd draft" (Box 61)
    - "Starr Bright Will Be With You Soon!", Work sheets; Intermediate draft (Box 61)
    - "Sunday Dinner: a Play", Early draft; Intermediate draft (Box 61)
    - "Tone Clusters", Work sheets; Early draft; Intermediate draft; Typescript ms. "3/7/90" (Box 61)
    - "The Truth-Teller", Work sheets (Box 61)
    - "Under/Ground", Work sheets (Box 61)
    - "Where Is Here?", Work sheets; Ms. draft (Box 61)
    - "Who Has Come to My Door?", See "Where Is Here?"
    - "The Woman Who Laughed"
      - Work sheets, 2 folders (Box 62)
      - Ms. draft "July 1994" (Box 62)
    - "You Must Remember This" (screenplay)
      - Work sheets (Box 62)
      - Typescript mss.
        - "Revision 12/22/88" (Box 62)
        - "Winter 1988-9", 3 folders (Box 62)
        - undated (Box 62)
  - Stories
    - "______" (working title: "Grosse Pointe Shores Mystery, 1979"), Work sheets (Box 62)
    - "Abandoned" (working title: "The Park"), Work sheets (Box 62)
    - "The Abduction" Seventeen, Nov. 1987 (Box 62)
    - "Acapulco Gold", Work sheets (Box 62)
    - "Accident", Work sheets (Box 62)
    - "Accursed", Work sheets; The Threepenny Review, Spring 1995 (Box 62)
    - "Accursed Inhabitants of the House of Bly", Work sheets (Box 62)
    - "Ace", Intermediate draft (Box 62)
    - "Act of Solitude" (working title: "How I Lost My Soul"), Work sheets (Box 62)
    - "Actress", Work sheets, intermediate draft (Box 63)
    - "Adultery" The Critic, Apr./May 1968 (Box 63)
    - "Adultress", Work sheets; New Woman, Jan. 1986 ("Adulteress" [sic]) (Box 63)
    - "The Affliction", Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "All the Beautiful Women" (working title: "Fashion"), Carbon typescript; The Saturday Evening Post, June 29, 1968 (Box 63)
    - "American, Abroad" (working title: "Distance"), Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "Anatomical Studies" Woman's Journal, May 1982 (Box 63)
    - "Angel Eyes" (working title: "Dancer"), Work sheets; Carbon typescript (Box 63)
    - "April", Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "Area Man Found Crucified", Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "The Artist", Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "At the Paradise Motel, Sparks, Nevada"
      - Work sheets, 2 folders (Box 63)
      - Typescript ms. (Box 63)
    - "August Evening", Typescript ms. (Box 63)
    - "Bad Girls", Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "Bad Habits" (working title: "My Honey"), Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "Bad Touch", Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "Ballad", Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "Bare Legs", Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "Beauty Salon" (working title: "Unisex"), Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "The Betrayal", Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "The Bingo Master", Intermediate draft (Box 63)
    - "Biopsy", Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "Black", Work sheets (Box 63)
    - "Black Water", Work sheets; Typescript ms. (Box 64)
    - "The Blessing" Sparrow 45 (Box 64)
    - "Blind", Work sheets (Box 64)
    - "Bloodstains" Harper's Magazine, Aug. 1971 (Box 64)
    - "Blue Skies", Work sheets; Intermediate draft (Box 64)
    - "Bodies" Harper's Bazaar, Feb. 1970; incomplete (Box 64)
    - "The Box Artist" Conjunctions, Spring 1999 (Box 64)
    - "The Boy" Playgirl, Dec. 1984 (Box 64)
    - "The Boyfriend", Intermediate draft (Box 64)
    - "The Brothers", Work sheets (Box 64)
    - "The Buck", Work sheets (Box 64)
    - "The Buried Self", Carbon typescript, with revisions; The Western Humanities Review, Summer 1997 - offprint, "author's copy" bearing signatures "Rae Jolene Smith," "Joyce Carol Oates" (Box 64)
    - "Capital Punishment" (working title: "Rapture"), Work sheets, intermediate draft (Box 64)
    - "Casualties" Chatelaine, July 1978 (Box 64)
    - "The Ceremony", Work sheets; The Southern California Anthology, Vol. XIII (Box 64)
    - "The Changeling", Carbon typescript (Box 64)
    - "The Child-Martyr" Fiction Midwest, undated (Box 64)
    - "Christmas Night 1962", Work sheets (Box 64)
    - "Color Blind", Work sheets (Box 64)
    - "Concerning the Case of Bobby G." The Atlantic, undated (Box 64)
    - "Conquistador", Punch, Nov. 8, 1978; Weekend Magazine, June 17, 1978; See also "Eine Frau von Format" (Box 64)
    - "County Detention" (working title: "Detention Center"), Work sheets (Box 64)
    - "The Crossing", Work sheets (Box 64)
    - "Crossing the Border" The New York Times Magazine, Dec. 1, 1974 (Box 64)
    - "The Crying Baby", Work sheets (Box 64)
    - "The Damnation of A-- K--" Fantasy & Science Fiction, (photocopy), Aug. 1989 (Box 64)
    - "The Date", Work sheets, intermediate draft (Box 64)
    - "Dawn, Dusk", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 64)
    - "Death Astride Bicycle", Work sheets (Box 65)
    - "Death Cup", Work sheets (Box 65)
    - "Death, etc.", Work sheets, intermediate draft (Box 65)
    - "Death Mother", Work sheets; 2 folders (Box 65)
    - "The Death of Dreams" McCalls, (incomplete), July 1971 (Box 65)
    - "The Death of the Kenyon Review", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 65)
    - "Death Valley", Esquire, July 1988; She, Feb. 1989 (Box 65)
    - "Death Watch", Work sheets; Intermediate draft (Box 65)
    - "December", Work sheets; Carbon typescript (Box 65)
    - "Deja Vu", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 65)
    - "Delia's Adventures", Work sheets; Carbon typescript (Box 65)
    - "Demon", Work sheets (Box 65)
    - "Depot", Work sheets; 3 folders (Box 65)
    - "Did You Ever Slip on Red Blood?" Harper's Magazine, Apr. 1972 (Box 65)
    - "Dies Irae", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 65)
    - "The Disappearance", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 65)
    - "Do With Me What You Will" Playboy (incomplete), undated (Box 65)
    - "Don't You Trust Me?" (working title: "Dr. Night"), Work sheets (Box 65)
    - "The Double-Edged Knife" (alternate title: "The Knife"), Work sheets; Typescript ms.; Redbook, May 1987; She, June 1988 (Box 65)
    - "The Dream-Catcher", Work sheets (Box 66)
    - "Early Winter", Beacon, Jan. 27, 1985; Sunday Journal Magazine, Sept. 30, 1984 (Box 66)
    - "Eleutheria", Typescript ms. (Box 66)
    - "Elvis Is Dead: Why Are You Alive?", Work sheets (Box 66)
    - "Embrace", Intermediate draft; Typescript ms. (Box 66)
    - "Emergency", Work sheets (Box 66)
    - "The Enchanted Piano" [n.p.], June 1971 (Box 66)
    - "The Escape", Work sheets (Box 66)
    - "The Evening and the Morning", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 66)
    - "Extenuating Circumstances", Work sheets (Box 66)
    - "Faithless", Work sheets; Intermediate draft (Box 66)
    - "The False Mirror", Work sheets (Box 66)
    - "Family", Work sheets; Typescript ms. (with revisions) (Box 66)
    - "A Far Countree", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 66)
    - "Fever", Work sheets (Box 66)
    - "Fever Blisters", Work sheets (Box 66)
    - "Fin de Siecle", Work sheets; Esquire (German ed.) [n.d.] (Box 66)
    - "First Death", Carbon typescript; Mademoiselle, June 1978 (Box 66)
    - "The Floating Hospital", Work sheets; The Southern California Anthology, Vol. XIII (Box 66)
    - "The Footbridge", Carbon typescript (Box 66)
    - "Forgive Me!", Work sheets, intermediate draft (Box 66)
    - "Foster Home", Typescript ms. (Box 66)
    - "The Four Seasons", carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 66)
    - "Eine Frau von Format" Fur Sie, (translation of "Conquistador"), Sept. 28, 1988 (Box 66)
    - "Friday Night", Work sheets (Box 66)
    - "From The Life of.. .", Work sheets (Box 66)
    - "Fugitive", Work sheets (Box 66)
    - "Fugue", Carbon typescript, with revisions (Box 66)
    - "The Funeral" The Miami Herald Tropic, June 19, 1983 (Box 66)
    - "Gay" Playboy (incomplete), undated (Box 66)